American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 29, 1895; 7x4-1/2; Kimball, James P. (James Putnam), 1836-1913
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends check for copy of Gabb's Santo Domingo. Asks for copy of index to the Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 30, 1895; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trübner & Co., Ltd.
    London, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Orders copy of McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], March 31, 1895; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Kimball, James P. (James Putnam), 1836-1913
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for copy of index to the Transactions.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], April 2, 1895; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Appoints Phillips, Greene and Smyth to committee on Lyman's paper, "Folds and faults in Pennsylvania anthracite beds."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 3, 1895; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Ballantyne, William & sons
    Washington, L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends check for purchase of publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 3, 1895; 8x5-1/4; California Academy of Sciences
    San Francisco, Cal., A.L.S.: Frank H. Vaslit. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for Transactions.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], April 3, 1895; 8x5; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Phillips wants Lyman's paper to present to committee meeting.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, April 4, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns illustrations for (unpublished?) paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 5, 1895; 10x8; Goodfellow, Edward, 1828-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns subscriptions to his publications. Refers to Phillips, Houston, Bache.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 6, 1895; 7x4-1/2; Hartshorne, Henry, 1823-1897
    Germantown, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his obituary of J.E. Rhoads. Refers to Fraley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 10, 1895; 10-3/4x8-1/4; University of Wyoming
    Laramie, Wyo., L. 1p. Requests copies of H.C. Baird's paper on "Association: the Dominating Need of Man." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 33, pp. 134-140.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, April 11, 1895; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    [Phila.] A.L.S.: F[rederick] D. Langenheim 1p. Society has catalogued A.P.S. collection now at Museum and wishes to turn it back to the A.P.S. Refers to D. Dorr.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 13, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; DaCosta, Jacob Mandes, 1833-1900
    [Phila.], L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for title-page of Proceedings, vol. 33.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 14, 1895; 13-1/2x8-3/4; Garczynski, Edward R.
    Mexico [City], A.L.S. 2p. Asks aid in project of photographing Mexican antiquities. Refers to job as N.Y. Times correspondent at Centennial.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, April 15, 1895; 6x8; Baird, Henry Carey, 1825-1912
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends requested copies of his paper on "Association" for the University of Wyoming. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 33, pp. 134-140.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, April 15, 1895; 8 1/2x5 1/4; Dorr, Dalton
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns A.P.S. numismatic collection. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 34, pp. 165-166.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 16, 1895; 11x8-1/2; Georgia Historical Society
    Savannah, Ga., A.L.S.: Otis Ashmore, Cor. Sec. 1p., end. Asks to have set of slides made from astronomical photographs presented to A.P.S. by I. Roberts.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 16, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., L. 6p., end. Concerns his obituary of T.H. Dudley. Refers to another of J.F. Garrison.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, April 17, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Has appointed Patterson, Cope, Brinton and Rosengarten to prepare obituaries of Vaux, Ryder, Ruschenberger and Coppée, respectively.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 17, 1895; 10-1/2x8; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from W.G. Farlow, endorsing an unidentified paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 18, 1895; 9x7; Calvert, Philip Powell, b. 1871
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns printing of addresses made at J.A. Ryder Memorial Meeting.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, April 18, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 3p. Concerns illustrations for (unpublished?) paper.
  - Motion to refer letters of D. Dorr and F. D. Langenheim, April 19, 1895; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    with list of A.P.S. numismatic collection, to the Curators; Phila., D. 1p.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, April 19, 1895; 9x6; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: F. D. Langenheim 1p. Enc. Sending list of A.P.S. numismatic collection. Encloses self-addressed envelope.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morrison [sic], April 19, [1895]; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting. Sends nominations. Requests various publications. Refers to Phillips prize committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from Potts about his obituary of T.H. Dudley. Refers to Phillips' illness. For enclosure, see Potts to Fraley, April 16, 1895.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 22, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Lindsay, James, 1852-1923
    Kilmarnock, Scotland, A.L.S. 4p., end. Enc. of 3p. Is sending copy of his "Progressiveness of modern Christian thought." Encloses printed brochure with excerpts from reviews. Askd to become A.P.S. member.
  - Letter to [William John] Potts, April 22, 1895; 3-1/2x8-1/4; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy. Concerns his obituary of T.H. Dudley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 23, 1895; 10-1/2X8; Farmer, Sarah J., 1847-1916
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns experiment at Greenacre, in Eliot, Maine. Refers to Franklin.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, April 23, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., L. 3p. Concerns his obituary of T.H. Dudley. Refers to Sachse, Horn, Edward Dudley.
  - Letter to Patterson DuBois, April 24, 1895; 11x8-1/2, 9x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Forwards copy of resolution dated April 19, 1895, asking Curators to arrange deposit of A.P.S. numismatic collection in Pennsylvania Museum.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, April 24, 1895; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p., end. Concerns numismatic collection. Refers to J.C. Morris, the Numismatic and Antiquarian Society. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 34, pp. 165-166.
  - Letter to [Patterson] DuBois, April 25, 1895; 11x8-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns responsibility of Numismatic and Antiquarian Society and the Pennsylvania Museum for A.P.S. numismatic collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 26, 1895; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns additions to his paper on marine fauna. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 135-154.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], April 27, 1895; 8x5-1/2; Howe, C. E., Co.
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends form to be filled in for Boyd's Directory.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 29, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Will read paper on "Some new forms of whalebone whales" at next meeting. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 34, p. 170.
  - Resolution calling for a comparison of various lists of the American philosophical society numismatic collection, April 30, 1895; 9x6; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., A.D.S.: Patterson DuBois 1p. Comparison of A.P.S. list of donations, the receipt of the Numismatic and Antiquarian Society, and proposed receipt of Pennsylvania Museum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 2, 1895; 11x8-3/4; The international mining and industrial exposition, Denver, Colo.
    Denver, Typed L. 1p., end. Asks for copy of catalog of A.P.S. museum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 3-June 6, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Milbury, M. J.
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal cards 13 pieces Reports on Phillips' failing health.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 4, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Enc. wanting Sends drawing for his paper on marine fauna. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 34, pp. 135-154.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, 1895; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Vaz Dias, Jacob? M.
    Amsterdam, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. In Esperanto. Asks to correspond on international language.
  - Letter to D[aniel] G[arrison] Brinton, May 8, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Agrees to appoint Heilprin, Ingham and Platt as special committee of experts on Lyman's paper.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], May 8, 1895; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Directions for printing notices of next meeting.
  - Letter to MacCalla and Co., Phila., May 8, 1895; 8x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., L. 3p. Copy. Asks for definite price on copies of his obituary of T.H. Dudley.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic], May 8, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., L. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends copy of his letter to MacCalla and co. His illness is very severe. For enclosure, see Potts to MacCalla, May 8, 1895.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic], May 9, 1895; 9x6; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends letter and asks her to notify members mentioned therein. For enclosure, see Fraley to Brinton, May 8, 1895.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic], May 9, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Potts, S. H.
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. W.J. Potts has received satisfactory reply from MacCalla and co.
  - Letter to E[lla M] Morison, May 10, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Platt, Franklin, 1844-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot serve on committee of experts to examine Lyman's paper. Refers to Fraley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 11, 1895; 10-1/2x8; State Library of Iowa
    Des Moines, Typed L. 1p., end. Orders set of Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 12, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Will read paper on "The Pamunkey formation of the Chesapeake region and its fauna" at next meeting. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 34, p. 338.
  - Letter to [Ella M. Morison], May 12, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., L. 2p., end. Concerns copies of T.H. Dudley's portrait, for use in his obituary. Refers to J.F. Sachse.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 14, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Concerns a drawing for a paper.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 15, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Boston Society of Natural History
    Boston, A.L.S.: Sam[ue]l Kershaw, Secy. 1p., end. Concerns its publication, Brigham's Historical notes on the earthquakes of New England, 1638-1639.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 15, 1895; 9-1/4x5-3/4, 3-1/2x6; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Concerns proof of a drawing for his paper. Refers to Ella Morison.
  - Letter to J[oseph] G[eorge] Rosengarten, May 16, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting. Returns pamphlets on French caves.
  - Letter to Miss Sallie Potts, Camden, N.J., May 16, 1895; 10x8; Dudley, Edward, b. 1849
    Camden, Typed L.S. 1p., end. by W.J. Potts Concerns addition of Robert Trimble's letter to W.J. Potts' obituary of T.H. Dudley. For printed obituary, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 34, pp. 102-134.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, May 16, 1895; 6-3/4x4-1/2, 3-3/4x4-3/4; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., L. 4p. and add., end. Concerns addition of Robert Trimble's letter to Pott's obituary of T.H. Dudley. Refers to MacCalla and co.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 17, 1895; 3 1/2x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns drawing for a paper.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morison, May 17, 1895; 10-1/2x8; State Library of Iowa
    Des Moines, Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns purchase of a set of the Transactions.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morrison [sic], May 18, 1895; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns election of new members. Refers to Horn, Brinton, Phillips prize, G.F. Edmunds.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morrison [sic], May 21, 1895; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Gives address of Georges Bertin.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, May 21, [1895]; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns supplement to Potts's obituary of T.H. Dudley. Refers to his remarks on work of F.H. Cushing.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 23, 1895; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Sends addition to his paper.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morrison [sic], May 28, 1895; 8x5, 9x5-3/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. of 2p. MS. list Asks for proofs of minutes and list of new members. Refers to Phillips prize. Enclosure is list of new members in Miss Morison's hand.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 31, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Pearse, John Barnard, 1842-1914
    Roxbury, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copies of F.M. Day's Microscopic examination of timber, and J.T. Rothrock's Some microscopic distinctions between good and bad timber. For printed papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol.21, pp. 333-342, and vol. 20, pp. 599-604.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, June 1, [1895]; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his obituary of Henry Coppée.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 3, 1895; 8x5; Lehigh University
    South Bethlehem, Pa., L.S.: W.H. Chandler, Acting President 1p., end. Death of Henry Coppée.
  - Letter to John G[riffith] Ames, June 4, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., L. 2p. Copy. Congratulates him on his index of public documents. Mentions Phillips' illness.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morrison [sic], June 5, 1895; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of by-laws.
  - Letter to [Ella M] Morison, June 5, [1895]; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Question about by-laws.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, June 6, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns text of his remarks on work of F.H. Cushing. See A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 34, p. 338. Refers to H. Phillips' illness.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 6, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Pearse, John Barnard, 1842-1914
    Roxbury, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about prices of papers by Day and Rothrock.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 7, 1895; 10-1/2x8; State Library of Iowa
    Des Moines, Typed L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Sends draft to cover purchase of set of the Transactions.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morison, June 7, 1895; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Death of Henry Phillips.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 7, 1895; 11x8-1/2, 8-3/4x5-1/2, 6x4-1/2; Trübner, Karl J.
    Strassburg, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Encs. of 7 p. of printed matter Asks for information on A.P.S. to be included in Minerva. Sends printed advertisements of the publication.
  - Letter to [John Barnard Pearse], June 7, [1895]; 4-3/4x8-1/2; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila.], A.L. 1p. Draft. Concerns his right as member to receive the Proceedings.
  - Letter to Frederick D. Langenheim, June 10, 1895; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed copy 1p. Concerns pieces missing from A.P.S. numismatic collection after deposit with Numismatic and Antiquarian Society.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 10, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Pearse, John Barnard, 1842-1914
    Roxbury, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Has bought the publications from A.E. Foote.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 11, 1895; 8x5; Love, W. K.
    Riverside, Cal., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting. Death of Daniel Kirkwood. Returns his receipts for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society]:, June 13, 1895; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Murdoch, G. W.
    Milnthorpe, [Eng.], A.L.S. on printed sheet of advertising matter 1p., end. Asks for copy of report on "Franklin commemoration" (Sesquicentennial memorial volume?)
  - Letter to J[ohn] Sergeant Price, June 14, 1895; 11x8-1/2; Spangler, H. W. (Henry Wilson), 1858-1912
    Phila., Typed L.S., with MS. additions. 1p., end. Concerns his resignation. Refers to Henry Phillips.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2, 3-1/2x6-1/4; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, Typed L. 1p. and add., end. Asks for copy of McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society Curators, June 17, 1895; 9x6; American Philosophical Society. Curators. Numismatic and antiquarian society of Philadelphia.
    [Philadelphia], A.L.S.: F[rederick] D. Langenheim. 1p. Is searching for pieces missing from the APS collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society Curators, June 17, 1895; 9x6; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    [Phila.] A.L.S.: F[rederick] D. Langenheim 1p. Is searching for pieces missing from A.P.S. collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 19, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Naturforschende Gesellschaft des Osterlandes zu Altenburg
    Altenburg, A.L.S.: Max Voretzsch 2p., end., and end. In German. Enc. wanting. Sends copy of letter of congratulation on Sesquicentennial celebration. Was omitted from list of societies given in Memorial Volume.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morison, June 20, 1895; 8x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns members in arrears. Refers to Harrison Allen's resignation.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], June 21, 1895; 10-1/2x8; Sellers, William, 1824-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for information on appointment of Rittenhouse and John Sellers to observe the transit of Venus, 1769. See Proceedings,vol. 22, pt. 3.
  - Letter to [John Sergeant] Price, June 22, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns Harrison Allen's resignation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 22, 1895; 9x5-3/4; Oliver, James Edward, 1829-1895
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerns her late husband's library. Will send his photograph if wanted.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 22, 1895; 3-1/2x5-1/2; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Order for McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morrison [sic], June 24, 1895; 10-1/2x8; Sellers, William, 1824-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of Proceedings, No. 119, with minutes concerning the Transit of Venus, 1769.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 29, 1895; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: W. C. Winlock 1p., end. Inquires about shipment.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 11, 1895; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Withdraws paper, "Folds and faults in Pennsylvania anthracite beds."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 11, 1895; 9-1/2x6; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, Typed L. 1p. Asks for prices of complete sets of A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], July 12, 1895; 10-1/2x8; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about continuation of C.S. Peirce's "The Algebra of Logic."
  - Letter to Mr. E. Morison [sic], July 16, 1895; 9-1/2x6, 9x5-1/2; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, T.L. 1p., end. Enc. Returns Morison's list of the volumes of Proceedings and Transactions, with further questions.
  - Letter to Ella Morrison [sic], July 26, 1895; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Geological Survey of Canada
    Ottawa, Typed L.S.: J[ohn] Thorburn, Librarian, 1p. Corrects address of A.R.C. Selwyn.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 3, 1895; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Pooley, H. C.
    Aldeburgh, Eng., A.L.S. 4p., end. Inquires about McCauley's Egyptian dictionary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 24, 1895; 9x5-1/2; Lackawanna institute of history and science, Scranton, Pa.
    Scranton, Pa., A.L.S.: Chas. LeR. Wheeler, Curator. 1p. Institute is being reactivated. Asks to receive publications again.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 27, 1895; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will read papers on Bucks County geology at next meeting. For printed papers, see: APS Proceeding vol. 34, pp. 381-384, 384-388.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 13, 1895; 8-1/2x5-1/2; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Orders McCauley's Egyptian dictionary for D.C. Eaton.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, Sept. 18, 1895; 10x8; Howard, L. O. (Leland Ossian), 1857-1950
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Death of C.V. Riley.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] S[tuart] Fullerton, Phila., Sept. 20, 1895; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Check, John M.
    Highgate, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Asks about early history of A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 23, 1895; 11x8; Colombia. Consul-general. New York
    New York, A.L.S.: Chicago Calderon 2p., end. Requests copy of Gabb's Indian tribes and languages of Costa Rica, for Vicente Restrepo.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 23, 1895; 5-1/4x8; Fullerton, George Stuart, 1859-1925
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from J.M. Check. For enclosure, see Check to Fullerton, Sept. 20, 1895.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 23, 1895; 11x8-1/2; Princeton University. Sesquicentennial celebration committee
    Princeton, N.J., Typed L.S.: Andrew F. West, Secretary 1p., end. Inquires about Latin name of A.P.S.
  - Letter to MacCalla & Company, Sept. 26, 1895; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Foot, Katharine
    Wood's Holl, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about buying copy of the Proceedings, No. 144.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 27, 1895; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Keyes, Charles Rollin, 1864-1942
    Jefferson City, [Mo.], Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for date of publication of vol.8 of the Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 29, 1895; 10-1/2x8; State Library of Iowa
    Des Moines, Typed L. 1p., end. Inquires about price of a set of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 2, 1895; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trübner & Co., Ltd.